- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh...
- ♪ 哦...
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[folksy music]
[民谣音乐]
♪
- Laser wrench.
- 激光扳手。
- Mm-hmm.
- 嗯嗯。
- Nope.
- 没有。
- Ah.
- Uh-uh.
- 啊。
- 呃呃。
- Mm?
- Not even close.
- 毫米？
- 甚至还没有接近。
- [laughs]
- No. No. No.
- [笑]
- 不，不，不。
- Ohh!
[honking]
- 哦！
[鸣喇叭]
- Ugh, fine! It'll do.
- 呃，好吧！就可以了
Hm?
嗯？
[doorbell chimes]
[门铃响]
- I'll get it!
- 我会得到它！
- Surprise!
- 惊喜！
[children giggling]
[孩子们咯咯笑]
Hi-ya, sis!
嗨，姐姐！
- Howdy!
- Auntie!
- 你好！
- 阿姨！
- Sandy!
- 桑迪！
' Oh, I didn't expect
y'all till tomorrow.
’哦，我没想到
你们都到明天吧。
- I know how much you love
your nieces,
- 我知道你有多爱
你的侄女们，
y'know, so I brought 'em
a day early.
你知道，所以我把它们带来了
早一天。
- SpongeBob, this here's
my sister Rosy
- 海绵宝宝，这是
我的妹妹罗西
and my three nieces.
和我的三个侄女。
This'n here's Macadamia.
- How do?
这就是澳洲坚果。
- 怎么办？
- Hazelnut.
- How do?
- 榛子。
- 怎么办？
- And little Pistachio.
- 还有小开心果。
- How d--[belches]
- 怎么了--[打嗝]
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
- Girls, this is my friend
SpongeBob!
- 女孩们，这是我的朋友
海绵宝宝！
- Aww, what sweet little
angels!
- 哇哦，多么可爱的小东西啊
天使！
- [laughs nervously]
Yeah, angels.
- [紧张地笑]
是的，天使。
Okay, well I gotta skedaddle.
好吧，我得溜了。
Freedom!
自由！
- Doggone it.
They're too early!
- 完蛋了。
他们来得太早了！
I'm not finished
with their present!
我还没说完
带着他们的礼物！
- Don't worry your pretty
little head, little lady.
- 别担心你的漂亮
小头，小女人。
I'll watch the
gals until you're done!
我会看
姑娘们，直到你完成为止！
- Thanks, SpongeBob,
but there's something
- 谢谢，海绵宝宝，
但有件事
I gotta tell you
about babysitting my--
我得告诉你
关于照顾我的——
- [chuckles] Yeah, I think I
know a little something
- [笑] 是的，我想我
知道一点东西
about babysitting, Sandy.
关于保姆，桑迪。
- [burps]
- [打嗝]
'Scuse me.
对不起。
- Y'all mind your
Uncle SpongeBob now.
- 你们介意你的
现在是海绵宝宝叔叔了
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Story time!
故事时间！
[inhales, blows]
[吸气，吹气]
Goldyfish and the Three
Sea Bears.
金鱼和三人组
海熊。
Chapter one,
breaking and entering.
第一章，
破门而入。
- Don't waste your breath...
- 别浪费口气了...
- And don't make a hassle...
- 别惹麻烦...
- Some kids like to read...
- 有些孩子喜欢读书...
[together]
But we'd rather wrassle!
[一起]
但我们宁愿吵架！
- Now you girls go easy on
me, okay? [giggles]
- 现在你们女孩们放轻松点
我，好吗？ [咯咯笑]
- One!
- [yelps]
- 一！
- [尖叫声]
[groans]
[呻吟]
- Two!
- 二！
- [straining]
- [紧张]
[chuckles] Ow!
[笑] 噢！
- Ugh.
- 呃。
Why don't ya show the girls
around town?
为什么不让女孩们看看
城镇周围？
- Great idea!
- 好主意！
I'll take them to the funnest
place in all of Bikini Bottom!
我会带他们去最好玩的地方
放置在所有比基尼底部！
The Krusty Krab!
蟹堡王！
Mr. Krabs, these are Sandy's
little nieces.
蟹老板，这些是桑迪的
小侄女们。
- Oh, nieces eh?
- 哦，侄女们是吧？
And what brings such cute
little customers
是什么带来如此可爱
小顾客
to Bikini Bottom?
到比基尼底部？
- We're visiting
Auntie Sandy...
- 我们正在拜访
桑迪阿姨...
- And we want to sling hash...
- 我们想要吊起哈希......
- A chophouse like this
must be...
- 像这样的小餐馆
一定是……
[together]
Loaded with cash!
[一起]
满载现金！
- Aww! Go on!
- 哇！继续！
No, really. Go on.
不，真的。继续。
- This is my coworker-slash-
best buddy Squidward.
-这是我的同事-斜线-
最好的朋友章鱼哥。
- Ugh. Children.
- 呃。孩子们。
- Ugh. Grownups.
- 呃。大人。
- This feller ain't happy.
- 这家伙不高兴。
- Just look at his face.
- 看看他的脸就知道了。
[together] We're gonna be sick,
all over the place!
[一起]我们会生病，
到处都是！
- [moans]
- [呻吟]
- [muttering]
- [嘀咕]
Here you go!
Three Dolly Patties.
干得好！
三个多莉肉饼。
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
- [imitates Krabs]
- [模仿螃蟹]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- Can you stop playing dress-up
- 你能别再玩换装游戏了吗
long enough to make some
Krabby Patties?
足够长的时间做一些
蟹肉饼？
[blubbering]
[哭泣]
- Huh! Guess that's me
all over. [laughs]
- 哈！猜猜那是我
一切都结束了。 [笑]
- [chortles]
- [咯咯笑]
You two look ridiculerous!
你们两个看起来很可笑！
- [yipping]
- [嘶叫]
- Ha! You're your own
worst enemy.
- 哈！你是你自己的
最坏的敌人。
- SpongeBob, from now on
——海绵宝宝，从现在开始
babysit off Krusty Krab
Property!
蟹堡礁附近的保姆
财产！
And Mr. Squidward, dress like
SpongeBob on yer own time.
还有章鱼哥先生，穿得像
海绵宝宝在你自己的时间。
- That place really stunk.
- 那个地方真的很臭。
- It was lamer than lame.
- 简直比蹩脚还要蹩脚。
- Take us somewhere fun.
- 带我们去好玩的地方。
[together]
Or taste Texas pain!
[一起]
或者尝尝德克萨斯州的痛苦！
- Aww, what cute little
knuckles you have.
- 哇哦，多么可爱的小东西啊
你有指关节。
Hmm, hmm...
嗯嗯……
ooh, I've got just the spot.
哦，我刚好有位置。
[funky music]
[时髦音乐]
[inhales] Ahhh,
[吸气] 啊哈，
smell that fresh seawater.
闻到新鲜的海水的味道。
Oh, heh-hey, right. Sorry.
哦，嘿嘿，对了。对不起。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[all yelp]
[大家尖叫]
[contented sighs]
[满足的叹息]
- [yawns] See, Sandy,
nothing to worry about.
- [哈欠]看，桑迪，
没什么好担心的。
Baby-sitting is eaaaaasy.
保姆是 eaaaaasy。
[snoring]
[打鼾]
- Hey, Uncle SpongeBob!
- 嘿，海绵宝宝叔叔！
- Huh?
- 啊？
- Open your eyes!
- 睁开你的眼睛！
- You're just gonna love...
- 你只会爱...
- Hm?
- 嗯？
all: Our sandy surprise!
所有人：我们的沙滩惊喜！
- It's our gift to you!
- 这是我们送给你的礼物！
- Well, isn't that sweet!
- 嗯，是不是很甜蜜！
- And it won't wash away...
- 而且它不会被冲走...
- 'Cause it's made of concrete!
- 因为它是混凝土制成的！
- Concrete, wha--?
- 具体的，什么--？
Good structural integrity,
girls, but a little tight!
良好的结构完整性，
女孩子，不过有点紧！
- So sorry, Uncle.
- We made it too small...
- 很抱歉，叔叔。
- 我们把它弄得太小了...
- But we'll get you out...
- 但我们会把你救出来...
both: With this wrecking ball!
两人：用这个破坏球！
- Wrecking what?
- 破坏什么？
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- [squawks]
- [嘎嘎声]
- [straining]
- [紧张]
Let's all go to my house
and take a little break.
我们都去我家吧
休息一下。
[moaning]
[呻吟]
[girls humming]
[女孩们哼唱]
Here we are, girls.
我们在这里，女孩们。
Pineapple, sweet pine--whoa!
菠萝，甜松——哇！
- I've been waiting all day
to watch your TV!
-我已经等了一整天了
看你的电视！
[eerie music]
[诡异的音乐]
- Patrick, you could have
watched it while I was out.
- 帕特里克，你可以
我出去的时候看了它。
- I forgot how to make it work!
- 我忘记了如何让它发挥作用！
Show me!
给我看看！
Show me funny!
给我看看有趣的！
I wanna see stories!
我想看故事！
Go, go! [sobbing]
走吧，走吧！ [抽泣]
Please!
请！
- Boop. There you go.
- 噗。就这样吧。
- I don't know how you remember
all this technical stuff.
- 我不知道你是怎么记得的
所有这些技术性的东西。
- Yeah. Patrick,
meet Sandy's nieces.
- 是的。帕特里克，
认识桑迪的侄女们。
- Good to meet ya!
- 很高兴认识你！
- Hey kids,
know what time it is?
- 嘿孩子们，
知道现在几点了吗？
It's nutcrackin' time!
现在是胡桃夹时间！
- [giggling]
I love this episode!
- [咯咯笑]
我喜欢这一集！
- Well, well,
what do you know?!
- 好吧，好吧，
你知道什么？！
[together] Patrick is watching
our favorite show!
[一起] 帕特里克正在观看
我们最喜欢的节目！
- Ah, finally, I can relax.
- 啊，终于可以放松了。
With work!
与工作！
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[slurping]
[发出声音]
- [straining]
- [紧张]
Hmph!
哼！
Ah, that's better.
啊，这样好多了。
[girls growling]
[女孩们咆哮]
Aww!
哇！
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
[girls giggling]
[女孩们咯咯地笑]
[growling]
[咆哮]
[girls yelp]
[女孩们尖叫]
[chortling]
[咯咯笑]
- Let's launch this goof...
- 让我们启动这个傻瓜......
[together] Right to the roof!
[合] 到屋顶了！
[chuckles] Lift-off!
[笑]起飞！
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
[all giggling]
[大家咯咯地笑]
Whoo! Whoo-hoo!
呼！呼呼！
- Who wants brownies?
- 谁想要布朗尼蛋糕？
Heh. I'll go make
another batch.
呵呵。我去制作
另一批。
[all giggling]
[大家咯咯地笑]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- Let's send this nit-wit--
- On his way!
- 让我们发送这个傻瓜 -
- 在路上！
- Before he ruins our whole
dern day!
- 在他毁掉我们之前
今天！
- Yeah!
- 是的！
[laughing evilly]
[邪恶地笑]
- All aboard for Glove World!
- 全体一起前往手套世界！
- Huh-huh-ha!
- 哈哈哈！
- Save me a brownie!
- 给我一个布朗尼！
- He'll be away...
- 他会离开...
all: The whole dern day!
全体：一整天！
[door opens]
- Hi! I brought some friends.
[门打开]
- 嗨！我带了一些朋友来。
- Ooh! I'll have to make more
brownies!
- 哦！我得赚更多
布朗尼蛋糕！
- All y'all shoo,
you're blocking our view!
- 你们都快点，
你挡住了我们的视线！
- Excuse us.
- Sorry.
- 对不起。
- Sorry, ma'am.
- 对不起，女士。
- We're taking that seat--
- 我们坐那个座位--
- Right where you sit!
- 就在你坐的地方！
- What you gonna do?
- 你要做什么？
all: Let's wrassle for it!
全体：我们一起奋斗吧！
- Ready, set...
- 准备好，开始……
wrassle!
扭打！
[bell dings]
[铃声]
[all straining]
[一切都紧张]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
♪
- Ooh, brownie!
- 哦，布朗尼！
[together] Huh?
[合]啊？
- You saved me one! Thanks!
- 你救了我一个！谢谢！
Guess I get the TV.
[chuckles]
我猜我得到了电视。
[笑声]
- That guy's mean!
- 那家伙太卑鄙了！
- Where's our auntie?!
- 我们的阿姨在哪里？
- We gon' leave!
- 我们要走了！
all: We want Sandy!
所有人：我们想要桑迪！
[crying]
[哭泣]
- Oh Auntie Sandy,
what a terrible place!
-哦桑迪阿姨，
多么可怕的地方啊！
- Everyone was so mean!
- 每个人都太卑鄙了！
- Right to our face!
- 就在我们面前！
- Aw, don't fret,
little ladies.
- 噢，别担心，
小女士们。
I made a present just for
you, you, and you.
我做了一份礼物只是为了
你，你，还有你。
- From a rattlesnake's tail...
- 来自响尾蛇的尾巴......
- To an armadillo's chest...
- 到犰狳的胸口...
- Our Auntie Sandy...
- 我们的桑迪阿姨...
[together]
Is the gol'durn best!
[一起]
是goldurn最好的！
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
- Oh, sorry, Sandy.
- 哦，对不起，桑迪。
I guess I'm just not a very
good babysitter.
我想我只是不是一个很
好保姆。
- I tried to tell ya the first
rule of babysitting my nieces.
- 我试着先告诉你
照顾我侄女的规则。
- What's that?
- Don't babysit my nieces!
- 那是什么？
- 别照顾我的侄女！
[together] Bye, Auntie Sandy!
[合]再见，桑迪阿姨！
Bye, Uncle SpongeBob!
再见，海绵宝宝叔叔！
- Bye, bye! Have a nice trip
back to Texas!
- 再见，再见！祝你旅途愉快
回到德克萨斯州！
Bless their evil little hearts.
祝福他们邪恶的小心。
[folksy music]
[民谣音乐]
- Ahhh.
- 啊哈。
[gasps]
[喘气]
Oh, no.
哦，不。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[together]
Hi, Maw! Did ya miss us?
[一起]
嗨，妈！你想念我们吗？
- [sighs]
- [叹气]